Nurudeen Saliu

An experienced FullStack and Perfomance-driven Engineer with years of working experience developing industry-ready applications. Strong knowledge of Typescript and Javascript with vast experience in building web applications using ReactJs for client-side, Node.js/Express for server side and MongoDB and PostgresSQL for database

24, Ibadan street, Ebute-metta west, Apapa Road, Lagos Nigeria.

+2347036509595

Email: saliu.nurudeen@yahoo.com Github:https://github.com/nurez305

KEY SKILLS

- Experience with various frameworks like ReactJS, Typescript, NodeJS and Express
- Experience in using GIT Version Controls.
- Experience with Agile software development and a strong understanding of the SDLC(Software Development Life Cycle)
- Extensive experience and knowledge of HTML, CSS, SASS, Tailwind CSS and Styled Component
- Proficient at using React, Node, Javascript/Typescript to deliver high quality, clean and well-structured production-ready code.
- Experience with the design and implementation of RESTful web services and APIs
- Experience with Test Driven Development (TDD)

WORK EXPERIENCE

Decagon, Lagos — Full Stack Software Engineer

MAY 2022 - DATE

- A member of a team that developed an Airtime 2 cash
- Produced clean, validation-ready code for project needs.
- Handled Database Management Systems with SQL like MySQL, Postgres, or NoSQL databases like MongoDB.
- Experience writing unit and integration tests.
- A member of a team that developed a duplicate transaction tracker.
- Built classifier projects with Nodejs, and Javascript.
- Exposure to agile methodologies.

SysServe Solutions LTD, Lagos — Front-End Engineer

FEB 2019 - APR 2022

- Work closely with lead developers to design products and solutions to different user and infrastructure problems.
- Communicate design ideas using user flows, process flows and wireframes
- Maintain standards compliance
- Ensuring websites are accessible across many platforms, including laptops and smartphones

TECHNOLOGIES

- HTML 5
- CSS 3
- Tailwind
- Javascript
- Typescript
- React
- Redux
- React Hooks
- Nodejs
- Express Framework
- GraphQL
- MongoDB
- Postgresql
- Heroku
- Firebase
- Jira
- Version Control with Git and GitHub.
- Test-Driven Development.

SOFT SKILLS:

- Collaboration
- Communication
- Critical Thinking
- Problem Solving
- Adaptability
- Time Management

- Fixing any website issues or bugs that arise
- Routinely testing websites for ease of use, speed and other quality factors.
- Active participant in daily scrum meetings and involved in many phases of confidential using agile methodology.

PROJECTS

Airtime2Cash App:

The Airtime to Cash app allows users to sell their airtime for cash. It features a wallet, which holds the funds users receive in return for sold airtime and allows for the withdrawal of those funds into the user's designated bank account. Other pages include the landing page, login, register, user dashboard, and admin dashboard for the confirmation of airtime transfers by the users. In addition, we added security features such as 2FA to the admin dashboard to secure the admin app in the event that admin credentials were compromised.

Technologies Used - React, Typescript, Nodejs, Express, Sequelize

Link: Airtime 2 Cash App

Github link: Github Repository

An E-Commerce Website:

A responsive e-commerce application built with react and stripe for product checkout.

Technologies Used - React, Stripe

Link: Ecommerce-app-link

Github link: Github Repository

A Meal Order App:

A responsive meal order application built with ReactJS and Firebase for storing the meal order data.

Technologies Used - ReactJS, Firebase, Css

Link: Meal-order-app

Github link: Github Repository

Youtube Clone App:

A fully responsive youtube clone app built with

React, Materia-Ui and Rapid-Api.

Technologies Used - React, Materia-Ui and Rapid-Api

Link: youtube-clone-app

Github link: Github Repository

Multi Page Website:

A complete responsive multi-page education/school website using HTML,

CSS, and javascript.

Technologies Used - Html, Css and Javascript

Link: multipage-website-link

Github link: Github Repository

EDUCATION

Kwara State Polytechnic — HND in Accounting

OCTOBER 2011 - JULY 2013

Upper Credit - Higher National Diploma in Accounting

From Kwara State Polytechnic

OTHER CERTIFICATIONS

Meta Programming With Javascript Link: <u>Programming With Javascript</u>

Meta React Basics Link: ReactJS

Meta Advanced React Link: <u>Advance ReactJS</u>

Scrum Fundamentals Certified (SFC)

Link: Scrum Certificate